6603 Tanglewood Bay Drive, Apt. 1205, Orlando, FL 32821

(801) 631-2604

Email: jax.a.lybb@gmail.com

Github: @jaxson-lybbert LinkedIn: @Jaxson Lybbert

Portfolio: https://jaxson-lybbert.github.io/Portfolio/

Jaxson Lybbert

Full stack web developer graduated from the University of Denver with a certificate in Full Stack Web Development. Logic focused programmer with excellent interpersonal skills, experience building intuitive and functional mobile-first applications. Excels in team based work, problem solving, and executing creative vision.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, Restful APIs, Git flow, Node JS, Express, ORM/MVC Paradigm, Handlebars, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, PWAs, ReactJS, GraphQL, Apollo Client

PROJECTS

Code Gauntlet | github.com/ryantixier/Code-Gauntlet | code-gauntlet-3e9a71d036dd.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Coding practice application where users can hone skills with different JavaScript challenges.
- Role: Back end model, database seeding
- Tools Used: JavaScript, CSS, ReactJS, GraphQL, MongoDB, MVC, Apollo Client

Fruit Finder | github.com/ThePebble01/fruit-finder | fruit-finder-f298ed9223ea.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Social tracking database for fresh fruit sightings across the United States.
- Role: Front end logic and design
- Tools Used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL, Express, Handlebars, Restful API, ORM, MVC

NHL Fan Plan | github.com/corynko/NHL-Fan-Plan | corynko.github.io/NHL-Fan-Plan/

- Summary: Dashboard for displaying stats for preset NHL team lists or for creating your own.
- Role: Logic
- Tools Used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Third Party API, Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

Momentum Solar, Orlando, FL — Solar Specialist

JUNE 2022 - JANUARY 2023

- Prepared analyses of customer's current and projected electrical usage, demonstrating financial return on investment via new system introduction.
- Gathered information from prospective customers to identify solar energy needs.
- Generated solar energy customer leads to develop new accounts.
- Produced quotes, proposals and contracts as part of sales process.

Verisys, Louisville, KY — Content Analyst

SEPTEMBER 2021 - JUNE 2022

- Compiled and maintained databases of medical professionals subjected to disciplinary actions.
- Analyzed medical board minutes and disciplinary orders to extract information for record.

Home Depot, Logan, UT — Flooring Sales Associate

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

- Discussed pricing, additional charges and payment plans during sales process.
- Maintained in-depth understanding of all available brands and types of flooring available to customers.
- Developed strong rapport with customers and created positive impression of business.

Harold B. Lee Library, Brigham Young University Provo, UT — *Library Clerk* AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2019

- Stayed up-to-date on library policies and procedures to smoothly enforce standards.
- Answered patron questions in-person or by phone regarding library services and resources
- Processed onsite and remote requests from patrons worldwide.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, CO — Certificate of Full Stack Web Development GRADUATED AUGUST 2023

Brigham Young University, Provo, UT— *Computer Engineering* AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2019

2.5 years completed at Brigham Young University

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Lakeshore High School}, \textbf{Stevensville, MI} -- \textit{High School Diploma} \\ \textbf{SEPTEMBER 2012 - JUNE 206} \\ \end{tabular}$